-
Speaker 1: And now, without further ado, please give a warm welcome to former Arizona police officer and radio host, Brandon Tatum.
- What's going
Speaker 2: on?
what's
Speaker 2: going
Speaker 3: on it's so wonderful to be here I
Speaker 4: can't believe how many people are in this room I can't believe how many Patriots
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): are in this room how many people who love this country who love God and who gonna stand for what's
right it
Speaker 6: just gives me energy
and
Speaker 6: when I see it all so what I want to talk about is two major things I want to talk about policing and I want to talk about the power of
the mind
Speaker 6: policing in America
the way
Speaker 4: people are portraying police officers today is shameful the men and women who put on that uniform who pin that badge
on
who walk
Speaker 4: away from their families,
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): their aspirations and dreams in their personal life to support, to
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): die for, perfect strangers should get a round of applause.
In my personal
Speaker 8: opinion, there is no greater
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): sacrifice than to die for people that you
don't know.
And police
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): officers do that every single day I want
to give you a
Speaker 6: quick story about how I became a police officer never thought about being a cop a day in my life I was growing up I got arrested when I was eight years old for smoking weed in a vacant house So my first experience with police weren't that it wasn't that flavorful in a good
way But I
Speaker 6: got to a point in my life where I need to make a positive decision as a strong man I had to support my child and
And
Speaker 6: I applied for everything in the city of Tucson. And the police department, that application was one of them. Never thought
about it.
Speaker 6: One night, I had a disagreement with my son's mom at the time, right? I think we were arguing about like an engagement ring or something like that. The next morning I wake up, I get a phone call from the Tucson Police Department. And I will never forget, I picked up the phone,
they
Speaker 10: said, it's Tucson Police Department, and I'm
like,
"She
Speaker 10: called the police on me.
Why would she do
Speaker 10: such
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): a thing?" And then they said, "Hey, Mr. Tatum, you apply for the job." And I'm like, "Oh, okay, yeah, yeah, whatever you need. Whatever y'all
Speaker 6: need, I'm
down now."
Speaker 6: But I knew nothing about policing. I only watched cops when I was young, so I knew nothing about what was going on. And I said, "I need to do a ride-along."
So
Speaker 6: I pulled up on the officer, his name was Sean Payne. I'll never forget Sean Payne. He's the greatest officer I've ever met. I pulled up on him in my private vehicle. I said, hey man, I wanna do a ride along. And he let me ride with him and it blew my mind.
We started
Speaker 6: from changing the flat tire of an elderly lady to going what we call code three, licensed sirens, 70 miles per hour down the road, almost died twice to save a kid who was currently trying to commit suicide.
When
Speaker 6: they kicked the front door in they went in I was able to look around the corner the kid was literally in the back cutting his wrist and Sean Payne saved his life and I'll never forget
that And so after all this
Speaker 6: happened Sean got in the car We got back in the police car and I remember my heart was just racing and
Speaker 6: Before we went to the car, he was asking me about my family. And so when we got back in the car, he began to ask me about my family again, and I couldn't even remember I had a family. I was like, "What are you talking about?" I was completely mind blown that that man had did what I saw him do. And at that point in my life, it's the first time I ever saw a hero, a real hero. Now I played football my whole life and I thought those guys were great. Nothing against football players and athletes.
Speaker 6: But when I saw that man
Speaker 12: turn into a hero and save lives, and he'd do it every single day, it impacted me.
And I became a
Speaker 12: police officer.
Speaker 13: Contrary to what some of these leftist lunatics will tell you, as a black
Speaker 6: man on a majority white Hispanic police department, I did everything on the police department. I was a field training officer. I was a general instructor. I was on the SWAT team. I was a spokesperson for the police department. That mean I represented the police department in front of the news, representing our values and different things that we had to speak on. I did all of those things. And I loved every minute of my service as a police
Speaker 4: officer.
Speaker 4: And today, I see a huge issue with the way they're portraying the actions of the
Speaker 14: men in blue today. I think it's a tremendous issue that I see because they perpetuate a complete
lie. This
Speaker 14: whole police
Woman 15: oppression, police brutality, it's a lie. It is a lie.
I'm going to keep
Woman 15: it 100. It's a lie.
do
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): police officers bludgeon people yeah that's far few in between they're not out here just hunting black folks down that's not happening I'm
Woman 15: not afraid of the police officer when I leave my house because I'm black they're gonna pull me over for no reason that's a lie
if I'm not
Woman 15: committing crimes then I'm not going to interact with
police often at all
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): and there's not going to be a time where a police officer is going to go gun me down while I'm sleeping in bed that's not going to happen they lied about what happened to Breonna Taylor they lied about what happened to Jacob Blake they
Woman 15: fluffed the story and what happened to George Floyd they leave out details that leave black people afraid and
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): terrified when
they
Speaker 4: shouldn't be I
tell young
Speaker 4: people all the
time
Don't
Speaker 4: be afraid of the police. Won't you become a police officer? Won't
you pick up an
Speaker 4: application put down a protest the signs and all that stuff? Why don't
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): you become a police officer so you can patrol in your community and you can be the difference that you want to see?
How is that
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): too difficult?
And I want to say this
Speaker 6: because it
Speaker 4: just this is the story that's hot right now And it's just made it made my brain explode Why in the world?
Speaker 17: Jacob Blake's name on football helmets. Why
Woman 15: are their names on the back of jerseys being flaunted as individuals who are heroic? There is nothing heroic about assaulting a woman, fighting police officers, trying to go to the front of the
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): car with a knife in your hand. There's
Speaker 18: nothing heroic
about that.
And nobody
Speaker 18: wanna keep it real, but I'm gonna keep it real.
There is no
Speaker 14: excuse to resist arrest.
And I tell
Speaker 14: young people this all the time. I can't control what every police officer does. You can
Speaker 6: only train them so much. What do you expect, they're not God. But what you can do is you control how you react to police
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): officers.
When
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): they pull you over, follow the law, follow the rules. Sometimes you may be pulled over for no reason. It doesn't matter. But what you can control is what matters. Put your hands on the steering wheel. Be respectful. It's not a debate. This is not curbside justice. You don't need to make a point right now. You
need to
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): live through this interaction. And
it's not
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): just reserved for black people.
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): It's for all of us. We
all get
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): pulled over by police. And as a former police officer, it's no one color or one race that I'm more afraid of. And I'm not afraid of race in general. I'm afraid of a gun. I'm afraid of you killing me. It has nothing to do with your race. And when we decide as a society,
to
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): work on the introspective
Speaker 19: portion, meaning working on yourself and how you interact, I think we'll have better interactions with police officers.
I want to jump into another
Speaker 6: subject along those same lines, but a gentleman I was debating with, we were at a church, it wasn't a debate, it was a conversation.
And the
Speaker 6: reason why we were able to have a conversation and not necessarily a debate is because we understood one fundamental principle is that we're both children
of God. We
Speaker 14: are children of God first. That goes beyond politics, that
Speaker 6: goes beyond anything else. So we were able to have a dialogue and a conversation. One thing that bothered me
Speaker 4: that this man said,
and I
Speaker 4: have the utmost respect for him, is that he had mentioned that he cannot wait to the day
Speaker 4: where his child
Speaker 6: or grandchild, he's a black man, will have the same opportunities as the white pastor's grandchildren.
And
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): it bothered me a little bit as a Christian because I'm questioning, what God are you serving?
What God
Woman 15: are you, who are you reading about? Because the last time I checked,
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): there is no door
A
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): white man is going to close that God has already opened for me.
I don't believe
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): in white privilege. I believe
in
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): Christ's privilege. And
for the life of
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): me, I could not understand how that pastor could perceive things that way.
Because you
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): become what you believe in your mind.
If you're
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): walking around every day and you're perceiving you're gonna have negative interactions with you're
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): gonna have negative interactions If you're walking around and you think everybody's after you the white man is
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): following me around and everywhere I go and they just trying to get me. I got to work three or four times as hard as everybody else
Woman 15: That's what you're gonna get But
if you
Woman 15: keep in your mind that I'm a powerful child of God Meaning that the words that
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): I speak will be manifested in
The
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): things that I say, the God that I serve can manifest the things that I want to happen.
And if you
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): believe that, you will achieve it.
I do not
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): waste a moment of my life
Speaker 14: complaining and making excuses. Excuses will get you nowhere in life. Nowhere.
I spend my time
Speaker 12: dreaming.
Speaker 12: About accomplishing great things
Speaker 4: for other people and
that's the
Speaker 4: difference Serving is where we build who we are service if you want to be successful or the things that you want to see happen you need to serve another
Speaker 6: person in that manner for instance if You want to be prosperous when it when you when it comes to money finances then how about you give
a
to
Speaker 6: other people and help them become prosperous. That's how it will come back to you.
And I
Speaker 4: just, I really want us to hone in on this, is the service component. We need to serve more. We need to have the servant mentality
Speaker 14: more.
Our minds
Speaker 14: shouldn't be to argue or be upset with our brothers and sisters. How can I
Speaker 4: love you and serve you like Christ would? How do we do that?
And
Speaker 4: once we start getting to that level, I think that
Speaker 14: we'll see a better America. We'll
see a
Speaker 14: better place. And it makes me happy to see everybody in here, of all races, colors, ages, you name it, sitting here
Speaker 6: together, listening to such a good event. And when I see that, I see an example of what America really
looks like.
This is America. This is America. Where we love one another,
Speaker 20: we
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): appreciate one another,
we can sit
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): next to one another, not looking at
color of your skin,
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): where you came from, where you're
Speaker 21: going,
but that we are all
Speaker 21: children.
Of the
Speaker 21: most high God
In this it's really
Speaker 21: that simple It's
Speaker 6: that simple. It's that simple.
I Want to finish
Speaker 19: it with this and if anybody watch my YouTube channel, I say I'm gonna finish and I'm about 30 40 more minutes And I'm still
talking But I think we
Speaker 6: need to be active in our pursuit
of
Speaker 6: political things right this event is not about Republican or Democrat I could care less
my
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): the way I look at politics the way I look at life everything in
Speaker 13: my life I look at it from this from a spiritual sense what would Christ
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): want me to do in this arena
when you talk
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): about crucial things like abortion gay marriage all that stuff that make people
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): all weird on the inside
You
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): should be focusing on what is God saying about this and
When I look
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): at what God says about who you who you should marry what marriage really is When I look at what God is saying about giving life, I believe that life starts at conception not perception
When you look at
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): those things
That's where you
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): should get your political stance from not these party lines
And I
Speaker 6: find it very mysterious when I see Christians going on a side that's counterproductive to Christ, counterproductive
Speaker 22: to God. How
in the
Speaker 22: world, how in the
world are
Speaker 22: you Christian and you see these
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): politicians out here advocating for you to go to a clinic and get rid of God's children?
Every
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): time you get rid of a life, that belongs to God. That's not yours. How
do you support
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): politicians like that? It
is
Speaker 4: beyond me.
When you
Speaker 4: see politicians that are more concerned with the same-sex
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): thing than they are concerned with the house of God, we have a
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): problem.
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): nothing and it's nothing against if you want to sleep with whoever you want to sleep with that's on you that ain't got nothing to do with me that's between you and God I didn't make the rules that's him don't kill the messenger but
at the end
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): of the
Speaker 16 (higher-pitched voice): day I want to see a person who's going to represent the faith I want to see somebody who's going to say no church can stay open because it's essential
I
Speaker 23: better stop before I start preaching. It's
Speaker 24: really that simple. It's
that
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): simple. It's that simple. If we actually produce what we believe, meaning that
Speaker 14: we stuck by the rudiments of Christ, stuck by the rudiments of what the Bible says, we're stuck
by the rudiments of what the Bible says.
there
Speaker 14: ain't no way in the world we won't be a better country there's no way we won't get
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): along more there's
no way
Speaker 11 (higher-pitched voice): we can't create policies to make everybody you know and not make everybody happy but be productive for each one of the people that are sitting in this room there's
Speaker 6: no way we can't do that
so i'll
Speaker 6: encourage you because i don't know what side of aisle you sit on and i don't even care i will encourage
you to
Speaker 6: think about what christ would do how christ would want you to behave.
And I
Speaker 6: want you to do that. And I just
want to
Speaker 6: finish by saying thank you.
Thank you guys
Speaker 6: for coming out here.
Thank you for being here. You could have been
Speaker 4: anywhere else.
You could have
Speaker 4: gone to any other event, which is probably hard to believe since Candace
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): Owens is here. But you could have done any other thing.
But
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): you found yourself
Speaker 9 (higher-pitched voice): dedicated, committed here to support the Blexit Movement. So I just want to say thank you. Give yourselves a round of applause. God bless you. And the show will continue.